let questionBank = [
  {
    "q-id": 1,
    "question": "The major organic compound formed by the reaction of 1,1,1-trichloroethane with silver powder is:",
    "options": [
      "2-butene",
      "acetylene",
      "ethene",
      "2-butyne"
    ],
    "correctAns": "2-butyne"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 2,
    "question": "At what temperature does the average translational kinetic energy of a molecule of a gas equal to the kinetic energy of an electron accelerated from rest through a potential difference of 5 volt:",
    "options": [
      "386.5e3",
      "3.865e3",
      "0.3865e3",
      "38.65e3"
    ],
    "correctAns": "38.65e3"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 3,
    "question": "Number of atoms in the following samples of substances is the largest in:",
    "options": [
      "127g of iodine",
      "48.0g of magnesium",
      "71.0g of chlorine",
      "4.0g of hydrogen"
    ],
    "correctAns": "4.0g of hydrogen"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 4,
    "question": "If the distance between the earth and the sun were half its present value, the number of days in a year would have been:",
    "options": [
      "64.5",
      "129",
      "182.5",
      "730"
    ],
    "correctAns": "129"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 5,
    "question": "The major organic compound formed by the reaction of 1,1,1-trichloroethane with silver powder is:",
    "options": [
      "2-butene",
      "acetylene",
      "ethene",
      "2-butyne"
    ],
    "correctAns": "2-butyne"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 6,
    "question": "A Carnot engine operating between temperatures T1 and T2 has efficiency 1/6 When T2 is lowered by 62 K, its efficiency increases to ⅓. Then T1 and T2 are, respectively:",
    "options": [
      "372 K and 310 K",
      "372 K and 330 K",
      "330 K and 268 K",
      "310 K and 248 K"
    ],
    "correctAns": "372 K and 310 K"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 7,
    "question": "Consider the system of equations x + y + z = 1, 2x + 3y + 2z = 1, 2x + 3y + (a2 – 1)z = a + 1 then: ",
    "options": [
      "System has a unique solution for |a| = √3",
      "System is inconsistence for |a| = √3",
      "System is inconsistence for a = 4",
      "System is inconsistence for a = 3"
    ],
    "correctAns": "System is inconsistence for |a| = √3 "
  },
  {
    "q-id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following is the contrapositive of if two triangles are identical, then these are similar?: ",
    "options": [
      "if two triangles are not similar, they are not identical",
      "If two triangles are not identical, then these are not similar",
      "If two triangles are not identical, then these are similar",
      "If two triangles are not similar, then these are identical"
    ],
    "correctAns": "If two triangles are not similar, then these are not identical"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 9,
    "question": "An unstable heavy nucleus at rest breaks into two nuclei which move away with velocities in the ratio of 8: 27. The ratio of the radii of the nuclei (assumed to be spherical) is:",
    "options": [
      "3: 2",
      "2: 3",
      "4: 9",
      "8: 27"
    ],
    "correctAns": "3: 2"
  },
  {
    "q-id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following functions have a finite number of points of discontinuity in R ([.] represents the greatest integer function)?:",
    "options": [
      "tanx",
      "x[x]",
      "|x| / x",
      "sin[πx]"
    ],
    "correctAns": "|x| / x"
  }
]

export { questionBank }